<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hypertension | L. Paloma Rojas-Saunero</title>
    <link>https://palolili.netlify.app/tag/hypertension/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://palolili.netlify.app/tag/hypertension/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Hypertension</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://palolili.netlify.app/images/icon_hud08db874d537f07f5a2207f5205ecb1e_175689_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Hypertension</title>
      <link>https://palolili.netlify.app/tag/hypertension/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothetical blood-pressure-lowering interventions and risk of stroke and dementia</title>
      <link>https://palolili.netlify.app/publication/eje2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://palolili.netlify.app/publication/eje2020/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;We aimed to study the effects of hypothetical interventions on systolic blood pressure (SBP) and smoking on risk of stroke and dementia using data from 15 years of follow-up in the Rotterdam Study. We used data from 4930 individuals, aged 55–80 years, with no prior history of stroke, dementia or cognitive impairment, followed for 15 years within the Rotterdam Study, a population-based cohort. We defined the following sustained interventions on SBP: (1) maintaining SBP below 120 mmHg, (2) maintaining SBP below 140 mmHg, (3) reducing SBP by 10% if above 140 mmHg, (4) reducing SBP by 20% if above 140 mmHg, and a combined intervention of quitting smoking with each of these SBP-lowering strategies. We considered incident stroke and incident dementia diagnoses as outcomes. We applied the parametric g-formula to adjust for baseline and time-varying confounding. The observed 15-year risk for stroke was 10.7%. Compared to no specified intervention (i.e., the “natural course”), all interventions that involved reducing SBP were associated with a stroke risk reduction of about 10% (e.g., reducing SBP by 20% if above 140 mmHg risk ratio: 0.89; 95% CI 0.76, 1). Jointly intervening on SBP and smoking status further decreased the risk of stroke (e.g., risk ratio: 0.83; 95% CI 0.71, 0.94). None of the specified interventions were associated with a substantive change in dementia risk. Our study suggests that a joint intervention on SBP and smoking cessation during later life may reduce stroke risk, while the potential for reducing dementia risk were not observed.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
